# **Andy Brummitt**

# Web Developer

21 Home Field Drive
Braintree
CM7 2DF
07562 010888
andybrummitt93@gmail.com

**Portfolio:** <a href="https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/">https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/</a> **Github:** <a href="https://github.com/Andybrummitt">https://github.com/Andybrummitt</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andy-brummitt-dev/

# **SKILLS**

Javascript | React | NextJS | CSS | SCSS | HTML | Node | Express | MongoDB | Git

#### **EDUCATION**

Writtle University College - BSc Hons: Sports & Exercise Performance 2014 - 2017 Grade: 2:2

# **WEB DEVELOPMENT**

I have two years experience in creating websites and an in-depth understanding of front-end development with Javascript and React.

My portfolio is the best representation of my work and shows my projects in more detail.

Portfolio Link: <a href="https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/">https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/</a>

Some of my individual projects are below:

**Bug Tracker** https://andys-bug-tracker.herokuapp.com/

This application is built with the MERN stack and aids development teams in organising bug and feature tickets within their projects. It utilises JWT authentication with access and refresh tokens with separate team and user auth portals and a MongoDB database on the backend to handle CRUD

operations. Once authenticated, users can create projects and tickets which allows teams to track and organise project development.

### Designmania <a href="https://www.designmania.co.uk/">https://www.designmania.co.uk/</a>

I was asked by a client to create a website for their limited company. Having been recently learning NextJS I decided to create the static site with NextJS and React as this duo can help a site be more performant with page load time and SEO compared to React's method of client side rendering. It was a fantastic experience to consult with the customer and bring their ideas to life.

#### Mixin <a href="https://mixinapp.herokuapp.com/">https://mixinapp.herokuapp.com/</a>

Mixin is a cocktail recipe web app that utilises the cocktailDB REST API to offer the user a seamless experience searching for cocktails that they can make. I built this website with vanilla Javascript even though it is a single page application. I did this to expand my knowledge of how React works under the hood.

# Chatty <a href="https://chattyapplication.netlify.app/">https://chattyapplication.netlify.app/</a>

This app is a serverless chat app similar to facebook messenger. The user can authenticate with google or sign up with their own email and password and can search for users by username to chat to. To test this application you can use any login details as long as the email format is accepted. I've created a couple of users that you can create chats with (the usernames are **test1** and **test2**).

# Battleship Game <a href="https://battleshipjsgame.herokuapp.com/">https://battleshipjsgame.herokuapp.com/</a>

This project is essentially a web based version of the popular board game, Battleship, with a graphical user interface. Users can battle against a bot that has been programmed to guess random tiles until it hits a ship tile, in which case it will guess tiles around the ship tile.

#### Summary

Despite not having any formal experience yet, I believe I have the passion and discipline to make it in this industry, having built apps and sites from my own intuition for the past two years. I am fully dedicated to this career and I feel that's reflective of my portfolio.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Order Fulfilment, Customer Support** - *Xylem Holdings (table-tennis-tables.co.uk)* 

May 2013 - PRESENT

Working in a relatively small company, I have had many roles during my time here. I started out picking and packing orders and handling dispatch but soon moved on to manage a small group of employees in the department.

As I was interested in web development, I am often asked to consult with my employer to make small changes on the e-commerce website using my HTML and CSS knowledge, though this is not my primary role.

Throughout my time I have regularly provided customer support which has given me lots of experience in dealing with a range of customer service inquiries.

# **Professional Ice Hockey Player** - Hull Stingrays

August 2011 - December 2012

After completing college I signed a professional contract with Hull Stingrays, an Elite League team. This was a dream of mine growing up, having played since the age of four. I played for the team until December 2012 when I was injured playing for Great Britain in the World Junior Championships in Ukraine. During this time I learned to remain disciplined and focused during times of struggle and reinforced my teamwork skills learned earlier in a professional environment.